[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
trien tasa Advanced Training till now I
published 44 YouTube videos covering
beginners intermediate and advanced
level Concepts the past couple of videos
I've started teaching you real time
scenario
and how can we automate your test cases
whenever you encounter different types
of
obstacles so this is our third obstacle
in this lesson I'm going to teach you
how can we automate a test case when you
encounter an obstacle where you have to
interact with a dynamically changing
table
elements basically this is not a table
but in your application this shows as a
table and it has an objects within the
cell which are dynamic in nature so you
need to interact with those
objects by using trient Tas so first let
us understand what is the obstacle in
detail so this is our third obstacle
which is categorized as hard in nature
so let's go for
it so here let's assume your application
under test generates an order ID every
time you click on the button
unfortunately it gets added to the table
randomly the order ID gets added to the
table randomly in any
row find a way to automate a table test
step that clicks on this
button and buffers the value of your
order ID generated within the
table enter the same ID into the text
box and now let's generate order ID here
let's generate order ID I don't see any
order ID in the table let's generate
this so now you see your order ID is
here third row from the bottom and your
order ID is 10
14851 let me generate again so now if
you see your order ID is in Middle now
and your order ID is changed that means
whenever you click on this particular
button the order ID generates
dynamically into any of the row now you
need to capture this order ID and type
the order ID in the
text how can we do do that let's go back
to trient
tasar and let us scan your application
right click on this folder click on scan
application so this is my application
click on
scan so if you see here you don't see
the table whatever we are discussing
here right
I don't see that so for that you need to
expand the filter click on again one
more time now you can see
here this is your table see
here Arana and then none AR none area
busy and false area busy and false But
If You observe closely see here this is
not a table at all this is a
container this particular table is under
a parent container called div and these
are all also containers see these are
all
containers and div containers right so
now how can
we capture this order ID so this is my
order ID right here Order ID and this is
my order ID so let's select this order
ID here
so if you select the order ID let's see
the properties here because this order
ID keeps on changing that means your
inner text does not remain same so
taking the property called inner text is
wrong so that's why I'm going to uncheck
this as soon as I uncheck now your
object is not uniquely identified see
here the selected object is not uniquely
identified so then what we can do so in
this case I can use identify by anchor
method how what is the anchor if you see
here this order ID whatever it is
generating that is generating exactly in
the same row where you have order ID as
a text so whenever you generate every
time this column and this column value
goes hand in hand
so that means I can uniquely identify
this object by using the column order ID
so let's select identify by
anchor now I want to use this order ID
as an anchor to identify this so for
that you need to click on this and drag
and drop onto anchor
control see as soon as I drop now your
order ID should be uniquely identified
see now here my order ID is now uniquely
identified so now let
us rename this module with the obstacle
ID
right so this is my
obstacle okay let's copy again
copy this and paste it here but along
with the order ID I also need to capture
the button and the text so for that
again go back to the
filters and here this is my
button which is uniquely identified and
this is my edit box which is also
uniquely
identified right now save this
module and close it so let's go back to
trasa here this is my new module that
has all the objects that we captured now
let us create a new test case here on
test case folder
obstacle and name this as the same
obstacle name
sorry I need not to create a folder but
I have to create a test case right click
and select the test
case paste it here now double click on
this now I have to drag and drop my
module onto the test
case so now what is
[Music]
our actions sequence of actions my
sequence of action is first I need to
click on order ID right before before I
capture the order ID here I need to
click on button order ID generate order
ID so but here the sequence of the
objects are not proper so let me make
them as logical order trag this and put
it here so
now click on this generate order ID
button and then capture the inner text
of this particular object
so if you see here the object name is
also not proper so it is a best practice
to name the objects in logical manner
because this order ID keeps on changing
so I'm going to make this as order
ID so now by default the object name
also changes in the test case so here I
need to capture the value into a buffer
how can I do that I need to use use the
action mode
buffer and
now I have to capture the inner text so
for that click on this
Arrow select inner text and I'm going to
store this under order ID
right done now I need to enter the order
ID into text so here I'm going to call
this
buffer for that
open curly
braces capital b square curly braces
order
ID
close Square braces and close curly
braces so here now I'm entering the
order ID from the buffer that I have
stored that means I'm entering the value
that stored under buffer called order
ID so now let us mark this test case as
complete now save this test case let us
execute the test case and see what
happens right click and run in
scratchbook so it clicked on generate
order ID and Order ID has been generated
and see here
1081 1656 by8 so the same number it
entered if you go back to your test
results
here here you can see your order
ID
1081 1658 has been stored under buffer
called order ID same thing we entered in
the text box so now let let me execute
one more time because whenever I click
on this button this order ID generates
dynamically in any row let's execute one
more time and see if it is going to
handle run one more
time see now it clicked on order ID your
order ID is changed unfortunately it is
actually in the
same row let me execute one more time
quickly see it's clicked on button now
your order ID is here not in third row
still it is able to capture and 1069
786 10 69 786 so it is able to capture
and type in into the edit box so if you
have any queries leave your queries in
the comment box I'll try to respond to
your
queries hope you all understand how can
we automate the test
case where you need to interact with
objects within the table that are
dynamic in
nature please do subscribe to the
channel on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos thank you
[Music]